Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Occupy.net Archived Website, Apr 28, 2012- ongoing; Occupy.net
  Occupy.net is a collection of tools for activists that provide people with software tools that align with the values of the Occupy Wall Street movement. All of the tools offered through Occupy.net are open source. The website maps, a forum, a directory, a wiki, projects, a classified section, and news regarding the Occupy movement.
  Distributive justice.; Social responsibility in banking.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy* Posters Archived Website, Jun 4, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Posters
  Occupy* Posters is a tumblr blog, established in 2011, containing posters created for the use in actions Occupy related movements. The asterisk in the name signifies a blank space for other Occupy groups, including location and issue-based groups. Posters are sorted by chronology, by topic, and by design type (including cartoons and infographics). Topics include social and economic justice, gun control, and political reform. The websites contains posters and examples of the posters in use.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Political posters -- United States.
- Occupy Albany Archived Website, May 5, 2012-Feb 4, 2015; Occupy Albany
  Occupy Albany is the Albany faction of the Occupy Movement, protesting in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street. The website contains general assembly and caucus meeting minutes, working groups information, and event/calendar listings.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility in banking.
- Occupy Alternative Banking Working Group Archived Website, Feb 24, 2015-ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  This is the website of the Occupy Wall Street Alternative Banking working group. The group aims to push for better financial regulations, by evaluating and fostering alternative financial options, and by educating the public about the contemporary financial system to inspire activism. The website contains event listings, information on their projects, reports, research resources, and a blog.
  Social responsibility in banking.; Banks and banking |z United States.
- Occupy Anniversary Spots Archived Website, May 16, 2013-Nov 15, 2013; Occupy Anniversary Spots
  Occupy Anniversary Spots is a campaign to raise money to put out video commercials for anniversary of the Occupy Wall Street Movement on September 17. The campaign uses the website, Louder, a fundraising internet platform, to raise funds. The website contains short videos and fundraising totals.
  Fund raising.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- OccupyArrests.com Archived Website, Feb 17, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Arrests
  Occupy Arrests is a running total of protesters arrested affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement since September 17, 2011.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Caravan Archived Website, Jul 7, 2012-Jan 7, 2013; Occupy Caravan
  Occupy Caravan, launched in June and July of 2012, was an educational road show in solidarity with the Occupy movement. The website features information on the events, the route, and a forum.
- Occupy Colleges Archived Website, Dec 11, 2011- Oct 6, 2014; Occupy Colleges
  Occupy Colleges is a college student activist group in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website posts news feeds on university and city occupations.
  Distributive justice.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Financial sector of the American economy.; Social responsibility of business.
- Occupycomix Archived Website, May 13, 2012-Nov 12, 2013; Occupycomix
  Occupy Comix is a comic blog featuring art inspired by and in solidarity with the Occupy movement.
  Comic books.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement) -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility in banking.
- Occupy Data Archived Website, Jun 14, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Data
  Occupy Data is an Occupy Wall Street Movement affiliated website that gathers data to analyze and create visualizations that are argument for their grievances on topics such as economic inequality, identity-based discrimination and inequality of opportunity, corruption, lobbying, campaign finance, militarization, the financial crisis, the criminal justice system, mortgages and foreclosures, and other themes. The website contains map visualizations, data sets, code for processing visualizations, and tutorials to create visualizations.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Political statistics.
- Occupy DC Archived Website, Oct 22, 2011- ongoing; Occupy DC
  Occupy DC is a nonviolent occupation of public space in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street and Occupy movements. Occupy DC was in McPherson Square in Washington during the Fall 2011 and Winter 2012, DC. The website contains event and action notices, news related to the occupation in DC, a blog called the Occupied Washington Times, a livestream, and a radio station.
  Social responsibility in banking.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.
- Occupy Design Archived Website, Oct 24, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Design
  Occupy Design, formed in 2011, is a graphic design project in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The project's goal is to create freely available visual tools around a common graphic language to unite occupy protesters. The site includes a showcase of existing designs, a how-to guide for demonstrators, a graphic toolkit for designers, and a platform for the community to suggest ideas for designs.
  Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.; Social responsibility of business.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Educated Archived Website, Dec 7, 2012-Sep 3, 2014; Occupy Wall Street's Practical Change Working Group
  Occupy Educated is an affiliate website of the Occupy Wall Street Movement's Practical Change Working Group that works to educate activists on issues and their root causes. The website works as a knowledge aggregator and provides a list of primer books, articles and commentary, and Author interviews. The website also contains blog and a forum for user contributions.
- OccupyFACE Archived Website, Feb 14, 2012-Apr 14, 2012; OccupyFace
  Occupy Face is a graphic design project to create a new symbol and "face" for the Occupy Wall Street movement. The artwork featured on the website was created by Paul-Felix Montez.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Graphic artists |z United States.
- Occupy Foreclosure Archived Website, Sep 10, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Foreclosure
  Occupy Foreclosure grew out of the foreclosure working group at Occupy Greensboro, North Carolina, now affiliated with the national Occupy Wall Street movement. Occupy Foreclosure mostly works out of the American Southeast to protect homeowners against foreclosure and make them aware of the resources to prevent foreclosure. The working group also works to make homeowners aware of corporate malfeasance and bank fraud that led to the housing bubble and recession of 2007-2009. The website contains information about their satirical film, "Let's Lose Our House," action updates, and news.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Foreclosure |z United States |x Prevention.
- Occupy Graduation Archived Website, Sep 13, 2013-Mar 14, 2014; Official Occupy Graduation Website
  Occupy Graduation, affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street movement, is a group which advocates student loan debt forgiveness. The website contains news and stories from students.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Student loans.
- Occupy Guitarmy Archived Website, May 1, 2012- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street Music Working Group
  The Occupy Guitarmy is part of the Occupy Wall Street Music Working Group, which was founded as part of the Occupy Wall Street general assembly. They are a leaderless, participatory musical group that plays in the streets for progressive social change. The group organizes song shares and teach-ins. The website contains information about their current and past performances and events. The website is a tumblr blog that mostly contains videos.
- Occupy Healthcare Archived Website, Sep 12, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Healthcare
  Occupy Healthcare, affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street movement, works to build a nation-wide equitable, affordable, and universal healthcare system. They also believe in a patient-centered system built around prevention and wellness to improve health, as well as monetary incentives. They support the Affordable Healthcare Act and other political campaigns. The website contains a blog, personal stories about the failures of the current healthcare system, and information about doctors in support of the campaign.
  Single-payer health care.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Physicians -- Political activity
- Occupy Homecoming Archived Website, Jun 1, 2013-Sep 1, 2013; Occupy Homecoming
  The website contains information to the June 1, 2013 attempted reoccupation of Liberty Plaza in New York City by activists affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement. The demonstrations were in solidarity with protesters against plans to replace Taksim Gezi Park in Cairo, Egypt with a shopping mall. The website contains event listings and a forum.
- Occupy Judaism Archived Website, Sep 23, 2012-Jun 23, 2013; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  Occupy Judaism mobilizes Jewish participation in Occupy Wall Street, bringing the Jewish prophetic voice to bear on issues of social and economic injustice, and brings the values of Occupy back into the Jewish community. Occupy Judaism is nonsectarian, nondenominational, and open to Jews and their non-Jewish partners. The website features a blog, videos, and information on their events.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Judaism and politics.
- Occupy Money Cooperative Archived Website, Aug 29, 2013-Aug 27, 2014; Occupy Money Cooperative
  The Occupy Money Cooperative (OMC) is a venture to establish transparent, low-cost financial services to all. The first project of OMC is the "Occupy Card," which is a prepaid debit card with a transparent fee structure, featured prominently on the website. The website contains fundraising information, a blog, and information about the co-op and structure.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Consumer cooperatives.
- Occupy National Gathering Archived Website, Jun 30, 2012-Feb 2, 2013; Occupy National Gathering
  The Occupy National Gathering, which took place on July 4, 2012 in Philadelphia, was a gathering of groups in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website contains the findings from the gathering, news, solidarity groups, and upcoming actions.
- Occupy Network Archived Website, Aug 28, 2013-Nov 28, 2014; Occupy Network
  The Occupy Network is a discovery portal for the Occupy Wall Street (OWS) movement and is the home of the OWS Newsletter.
- Occupy News Archived Website, Dec 4, 2011- ongoing; Occupy News
  Occupy News is a news website that aggregates news on over 175 occupations that are part of the Occupy Wall Street movement across the United States.
  Distributive justice.; Banking law.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Social responsibility in banking.
- Occupy Our Homes Archived Website, Dec 10, 2011- ongoing; OccupyOurHomes
  OccupyOurHomes is a website inspired about the Occupy Movement. The website works to negotiate with Wall Street banks and homeowners instead of foreclosing on homeowners. They believe that everyone has the right to affordable housing. Activists occupy foreclosed homes to work for change. The website contains videos, articles, and resources on how to protect homes from foreclosure.
- Occupy People's ThinkTank Archived Website, Jul 26, 2012-Jan 26, 2014; Occupy People's Think Tank
  Occupy Wall Street People's Think Tank, formed in September 2011, holds open dialogues throughout New York City. The website features summaries and recordings of these conversations.
- Occupy Pics Archived Website, Dec 5, 2011-Jun 15, 2014; Occupy Pics
  Occupy Pics is a blog that posts pictures and videos from the Occupy Wall Street Movement.
  Social responsibility in banking.; Distributive justice.; Banking law.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Resistance Archived Website, Dec 10, 2011-Mar 19, 2013; Occupyr.com
  Occupyr is a social networking website and provides web-infrastructure and tech support for the Occupy Movement. Occupyr aims to assist in unifying protesters into actionable plans to strengthen the movement. The website has a livestream, news feed, forums, an art page, and a chat room dedicated to the Occupy movement.
  Social responsibility in banking.; Distributive justice.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- OCCUPYSMS: Mutual Aid Platform Archived Website, Dec 4, 2012-Jun 1, 2014; Occupy SMS
  OccupySMS, established in the wake of Superstorm Sandy in October 2012, expedites mutual aid by connecting people through text message by seeking and offering aid based on specific location and needs in areas without power or Internet.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Hurricane Sandy, 2012.
- Occupy Stories Archived Website, Mar 25, 2013-Jun 25, 2014; Occupy Stories
  Occupy Stories, founded in November 2011, aims to collect and organize stories and observations from the Occupy movement. Most of the stories on the website are of a personal nature, detailing stories on individual experiences of those involved in the movement. The website also has has a forum for discussion.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility of business.; Financial sector of the American economy.
- Occupy Student Debt Archived Website, Jun 5, 2012-Dec 4, 2013; Occupy Student Debt
  Occupy Student Debt is a blog in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website collects user submitted stories on student debt that demonstrates the student debt crisis. The website contains demands, media, press releases, and resources.
  Student loans.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Student Debt Campaign Archived Website, Sep 12, 2013-Sep 11, 2014; Occupy Student Debt Campaign
  The Occupy Student Debt Campaign is an Occupy Wall Street movement campaign that advocates for tuition free public higher education, zero interest student loans, transparency of private university and colleges' financial records, and student loan forgiveness. The website contains a Pledge of Refusal that is framed as a debt strike threat (debtors pledge to withhold payments once a million others have signed). The website contains resources, stories of debtors, and an FAQ.
- Occupy Technology Archived Website, Oct 26, 2011-May 9, 2013; Occupy Technology
  Occupy technology lives as a storehouse for technological resources and ideas for the occupy movement.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Financial sector of the American economy.; Social responsibility of business.; Distributive justice.
- Occupy the Auctions / Evictions Archived Website, Sep 2, 2013- ongoing; Occupy the Auctions / Evictions
  Occupy the Auctions, affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street movement, works to stop predatory and for-profit bank evictions, foreclosures, and auctions of small businesses and homes, mostly in San Francisco. Organizers work through action alerts, research, and protests. The website contains a blog and sign-up forms.
  Foreclosure |z United States |x Prevention.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy the Board Room Archived Website, Mar 9, 2012-Mar 7, 2014; Occupy the Boardroom
  Occupy the Board Room is a site that provides those with a valid email account an opportunity to choose a "pen pal" in the top 1%, to whom they can voice their frustrations about America's economic issues.
  Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Social responsibility of business.
- Occupy The Bronx Archived Website, Apr 29, 2012-Oct 30, 2012; Occupy the Bronx
  Occupy the Bronx is Bronx's contingent of the Occupy movement in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street. The website contains action alerts, meeting minutes, a forum, and a blog.
- Occupy the Caucus Archived Website, Nov 12, 2011-Jan 21, 2012; Occupy the Caucus
  Occupy the Caucus, formed in Des Moines, IA, to occupy the Iowa caucuses in January 2012. They plan on occupying the presidential campaign headquarters in Des Moines, Iowa and other political events throughout the state for a week leading up to the caucus. The occupation plans to use the spotlight of the Iowa caucuses to make economic change.
  Elections |z United States |y 2012.; Elections |z Iowa.
- Occupy The Nation Archived Website, Oct 20, 2011-Dec 27, 2012; Occupy the Nation
  Occupy the Nation, established in late 2011, aggregates news related to the Occupy Wall Street and other occupations in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street. The website contains event listings, working group pages, videos, and a resource page.
  Social responsibility in banking.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.; Banking law.
- Occupy the Pipeline Archived Website, Jun 16, 2013- ongoing; Occupy the Pipeline
  Occupy The Pipeline is a grass-roots, not-for-profit environmental working group of the Occupy Wall Street Movement, founded in the spring of 2012, to oppose the construction of the Spectra Pipeline through non-violent direct action and civil disobedience. The Spectra Pipeline is a high-pressure, large-diameter, fracked-gas pipeline under construction in Manhattan's West Village, which is set to go on line November 2013. The website contains hydraulic fracturing (fracking) related news and events.
  Hydraulic fracturing |z New York (State).; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy the RNC Archived Website, Jun 13, 2013; Occupy the RNC
  Resist RNC, endorsed by occupy groups, was a coordination website for the protests and demonstrations around the Republican National Convention (RNC) in Tampa, Florida from August 27-30, 2012. The website contained event listings for all actions and counter- programming in Tampa during the RNC. Events included demonstrations related to economic rights, human rights, anti-war, and the environment. The website also features resources for activists planning events and protests. It also has a news blog.
  Republican National Convention; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Together Archived Website, Oct 6, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Together
  Occupy Together is a website that lists events and actions around the world in solidarity with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website lists major action projects of the Occupy movement, contains lists of occupy groups, and offers links to occupation planning websites.
- Occupy Union Square Archived Website, Jun 14, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Union Square
  Occupy Union Square is the website for the occupation of Union Square in New York City by individuals affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website posts occupy-related news, resources to support and get involved in occupy, organizing materials, and event listings.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Union Square (New York, N.Y.)
- Occupy Wall Street Archived Website, Oct 6, 2011- ongoing; New York City General Assembly
  OccupyWallStreet.org is the main website for the Occupy Wall Street Movement. This website contains news related to other Occupy movement sites, protests and demonstrations, and other social justice movements in solidarity with Occupy Wall Street. Occupy Wall Street (OWS) is a people-powered movement that began on September 17, 2011 in Liberty Square in Manhattan's Financial District, and spread to over 100 cities in the United States and actions in over 1,500 cities globally. OWS works to fight corporate banks' power over the democratic process. The website contains links to other Occupy movement websites.
  Banking law.; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility of business.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Wall Street Bike Coalition Archived Website, Jun 20, 2013; Occupy Wall Street Bike Coalition
  The Occupy Wall Street Bike Coalition (OWSBC) is a working group within the Occupy Wall Street Movement that provides bike swarm tactics for Occupy actions, free bicycle repairs, and fittings for bikes. OWSBC sees cycling as a sustainable transportation alternative. The group holds cycling meet-ups as well. The website contains event listings.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Bicycle commuting -- United States.
- Occupy Wall Street Care Packages Archived Website, Oct 26, 2011-Dec 9, 2011; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  This is a collection of notes, cards, and letters of support enclosed with contributions and care packages sent from across the United States and around the world to Occupy Wall Street.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.; Social responsibility of business.
- Occupy Wall Street Library, The People's Library at Liberty Plaza Archived Website, Oct 19, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  The People's Library is the collective, public, open library of the Occupy Wall Street movement. The library was located in Liberty Plaza in Zucotti Park in New York City during the height of the Occupy Wall Street Movement in late 2011. The facilities there and the collection were destroyed during the November 15 raid on Liberty Plaza. The Library consists of a book sharing system that lends free books in and out of the OWS storage facility and to Liberty Plaza and actions around New York. The website contains a catalogue of books, publications produced by the Library, and a blog.
  Libraries; Social responsibility of business.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.
- Occupy Wall Street Media, "Occupied Wall Street Journal" Archived Website, Oct 13, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement)
  The Occupied Wall Street Journal is a print and online newspaper produced by an affinity group of the Occupy Wall Street movement. The website contains news regarding the movement, analysis, and human interest pieces regarding the movement. The first newspaper was published in October 2011.
- Occupy Wall Street National Gathering Archived Website, Aug 29, 2013-Aug 28, 2014; Occupy Wall Street National Gathering
  The Occupy National Gathering was a gathering of Occupy Wall Street Movement activists in Kalamazoo, Michigan from August 21-25, 2013. The website contains logistical and scheduling information on the gathering. The website also contains news on other gatherings across the country.
  Meetings.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Occupy Wall Street Review Archived Website, Feb 14, 2012-Nov 13, 2013; Occupy Wall Street Review
  The Occupy Wall Street Review is the literary review of the Occupy Wall Street movement.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement) |x Periodicals.
- Occupy Wall Street S17 Archived Website, Sep 12, 2013-Sep 12, 2014; Occupy Wall Street S17
  S-17 2013 is the organizational website for the second anniversary actions (on September 17, 2013) of Occupy Wall Street at Liberty Plaza (formerly Zuccotti Park) in New York City. The website contains information about the events, actions, teach-ins, and marches held on the anniversary. Events are related to issues including economic fairness, politics and justice, war and conflict, social equality, and environmental protections.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Distributive justice.; Social responsibility of business.
- Occupy Wall Street Screen Printers Co-op Archived Website, May 13, 2013- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street Screen Printers Co-op